hamiltonbeach.com 2007-12-11

# Hamilton Beach:

| 

HAMILTON BEACH BRANDS, INC.  
PRIVACY POLICY

**Last Updated: September 7, 2006**

Your privacy concerns are important to us at Hamilton Beach Brands, Inc. ("HBB"), and we are committed to protecting your privacy. Please read the following Privacy Policy to understand how your personal information will be treated as you use this Web Site. When you use this Web Site, you consent to the use of your personal information by HBB in the manner specified in this Privacy Policy. This policy may change periodically, so please check back from time to time. For your information, the date of the last update to this Privacy Policy is stated at the top of this document. Use of the Web Site after this policy is updated indicates your consent to the changed terms of this policy. 

**THIS POLICY WILL EXPLAIN:**

  1. What Information We Collect From You, and How We Use That Information 
  2. How We Protect Your Information 
  3. Your Control of Your Information 
  4. HBB's Ownership of Information 
  5. Questions About the Privacy Policy 

* * *

****
  1. **WHAT INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW WE USE THAT INFORMATION**  
HBB does not collect any personally identifiable information from you (e.g., name, address, telephone number, e-mail address) unless you voluntarily choose to disclose such information. We will not sell, trade or rent your personally identifiable information to third parties. Your information may be used for research on usage patterns, product development, online site customization, targeted marketing, customer satisfaction surveys, customer purchasing habits or other purchasing information. If you do not want your personally identifiable information collected, do not submit it to us. 

Co-Branded Services: Some HBB services are offered in conjunction with a partner company. These are called co-branded services. In order to provide these co-branded services to you, it is necessary for us to share information with our partner company. If data is being collected and/or maintained by any company other than our partner companies, you will be notified prior to the time of the data collection or transfer. If you do not want your data to be shared, you can choose not to allow the transfer by not using that particular service. 

Aggregate Information: We collect non-personal information about our customers, and aggregate this statistical information in order to improve our Web Site. When we say that we may share such information in "aggregate" form, we mean that we will not disclose individual names, addresses, telephone numbers and e-mail addresses unless we have your permission. External companies may be provided aggregate information about our customers. 

Use of IP Addresses: An Internet Protocol ("IP") address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the Web. Web servers automatically identify your computer by its IP address. When visitors request pages from the Web Site, our servers log the guests' IP addresses. We do not normally link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable, which means that a visitor's session will be logged, but the visitor remains anonymous to us. HBB collects IP addresses for the purposes of system administration and to audit the use of this Web Site. We also use IP addresses to collect statistical information to send to our advertisers and for other marketing and promotional purposes. 

Use of Cookies: HBB uses "cookies" on this website because they help us in many ways to make your visit to our Web Site more enjoyable and meaningful to you. Cookies are text information files that your web browser places on your computer when you visit a website. HBB may use such "cookie" technology to obtain information from you as an online visitor. Cookies flag information about your activity on our Web Site. This information helps us improve our site and make it friendlier and easier to use. Most browsers accept cookies automatically, but can be configured not to accept them or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. We never use cookies to save passwords, credit card numbers or other highly confidential information. 

Use of Web-beacons: HBB may also use so-called "web beacons" to access the information contained in cookies within the network of the HBB web sites. Web beacons, also sometimes called "pixel tags," are small strings of code placed on a Web page or in an email message for the purpose of transferring data. HBB may employ the use of cookies and web beacons on our Web Site's pages to deliver our ads, to measure the effectiveness of advertising, including our email promotions, and to learn how visitors use our Web Site. 

Information from Children: HBB does not direct its Web Site to children under thirteen (13) years of age. No information should be submitted to this Web Site by persons under 13 years of age, and persons under the age of 13 are not allowed to register for newsletters, clubs or activities. Individuals under eighteen (18) should consult with their parent or guardian about the use of this Web Site for their benefit. Users under 18 years old are not allowed to make purchases or participate in contests. When appropriate, HBB may ask you to indicate your age to verify compliance with these policies. 

HBB does not knowingly collect information from our guests under 13 years of age or provide any personally identifying information from such guests to any third party for any reason whatsoever. We do not allow guests known to be under 13 years of age to receive direct marketing communications from HBB or from third parties. 

Monitoring, Enforcement and Legal Requests: HBB has no obligation to monitor the Web Site or the use of the Web Site, or to retain the content of any user session. However, HBB reserves the right at all times to monitor, review, retain, and/or disclose any information as necessary to satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process, or governmental request or to cooperate with law enforcement and other authorities in investigating a claim of illegal activity. We may use IP addresses to identify a user when we feel it is necessary to protect our service, Web Site, customers, or others. 

Change of Ownership or Control: In the event that HBB becomes owned or controlled by other individuals or entities, the information we have collected may be transferred to such party or parties. In this case, such individuals or entities will follow this Privacy Policy in the place of HBB's current owners. 

Other Sites: Except as otherwise expressly discussed in this Privacy Policy, this policy only addresses HBB's use and disclosure of information we collect from you. To the extent that you disclose personal information to other sites, you are subject to the privacy customs and policies of these other sites. We encourage you to ask questions before you disclose any personal information. 

HBB has and may add links to third party sites. Because such linked sites are not under the control of HBB, we are not responsible for the accuracy or reliability of any information, data, opinions, advice or statements contained on any such linked sites. Access to any other Internet site linked to this Web Site is at your own risk. HBB has not reviewed all of the sites linked to this Web Site. HBB provides these links merely as a convenience and the inclusion of such links does not imply an endorsement by HBB of such third party sites or any goods or services offered by such third parties. 

Advertisements: This Web Site may provide advertisements to its users. By clicking on an ad, you may be linking to a third party Web Site that is not controlled by HBB, and may have different information gathering practices than HBB. 

****
  2. **HOW WE PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION**  
Transmission Errors or Unauthorized Acts: Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, HBB cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or any information provided by our on-line products or services, and you do so at your own risk. HBB will not be liable for disclosures of your personal information due to errors in transmission or unauthorized acts of third parties. However, once we receive your transmission, we do our best to ensure its security on our systems by making reasonable efforts to protect the information. Security: Any information provided to HBB is treated with care and discretion. When information is shared, HBB will take a proactive approach to ensure the information is kept private and not misused. 
****
  3. **YOUR CONTROL OF YOUR INFORMATION**  
Your Choice: HBB respects your decisions about the collection and use of your information. You have the opportunity to elect to receive information about special offers from us. Based on this choice, you may receive information from HBB or a trusted third party. Every such communication we send to you will contain instructions on how to cancel receiving similar information in the future. By accessing and using this Web Site, you consent to the use of your personal information by HBB in the manner specified in this Privacy Policy. 

Update Information: If you have given HBB information in the past and now wish to change or delete such information, please contact us at: Attn: Webmaster, Hamilton Beach, Inc., 4421 Waterfront Drive, Glen Allen, Virginia 23060. Or you can contact us by telephone at 1-877-474-1122 (US) or (804) 273-9777. Although HBB will make reasonable efforts to make the changes you have requested, we may be unable to update other types of information provided to us, such as aggregate or cookie information or information that has been stored in our system. 

****
  4. **HBB'S OWNERSHIP OF INFORMATION**  
All opinions, ideas, suggestions, and other feedback submitted to this Web Site, may be used by HBB without any restriction and free of charge, and nothing contained in this policy shall limit or otherwise affect this. There may be instances where HBB requests or permits the submission of your opinions/ideas. In such instances you will be required to agree to the terms of an HBB prepared agreement related to the provision of such information prior to its submission. 
****
  5. **QUESTIONS ABOUT THE PRIVACY POLICY**  
Privacy and security is important to us all. We pursue a full-disclosure approach to responsibly care for the information you have entrusted with us, and we depend on information sharing as our principal means to best serve you. This is why we are committed to building a trusting relationship with you. We will continually monitor customer feedback and seek to improve our services to meet your needs. If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this Web Site, or your dealings with the Web Site, or would like to provide comments, you can send us an e-mail at [customerservice@hamiltonbeach.com](mailto:customerservice@hamiltonbeach.com), by mail to Attn: Webmaster, Hamilton Beach Brands, Inc., 4421 Waterfront Drive, Glen Allen, Virginia 23060. Or you can contact us by telephone at 1-877-474-1122 (US) or (804) 273-9777.
